johncabot.edu 2019-03-21

# Privacy Policy |John Cabot University in Rome, Italy | JCU | An American University Rome, Italy

**Commitment to Privacy  
** John Cabot University is committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. This statement describes our information collection practices and explains how we use and protect your personal information. Should you choose to provide us with any personal information, you can be assured that it will only be used by John Cabot University to conduct official University business, in conformity with [Italian law](http://www.garanteprivacy.it/home_en/italian-legislation). 

**Information collected and how it is used**

  * The JCU website automatically collects general information that does not identify you personally. This includes the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using; the web page from which you entered our website; the web pages you visited and for how long; browser used; date and time. To collect this data, we use Google Analytics, a web analytics service that provides statistics and tools that help us focus on the needs and interests of our visitors and improve the overall functionality of the website. Learn more about the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html). 
  * Personal information such as name, address, email address, and telephone number is collected on the website via voluntary inquiry and application forms.  Once you become a student, this information allows us to communicate with you.  Prospective students and alumni can opt out of receiving further communication from JCU by clicking on the opt-out option at the bottom of emails.
  * If you make a gift online or use our online payment form using your credit card information, we enter this information into our secure database. Once your gift or payment is processed electronically by a secure credit card processing service, your credit card information is not maintained in our records.

**Cookies  
** When you view our website, we may store some information on your computer in the form of a cookie, or small data file. Cookies enable the website to remember your actions and preferences over a period of time so that you don’t have to keep re-entering them whenever you come back to the site or browse from one page to the other. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any of your personally identifiable information while on our site. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience all features and content of our website. 

Learn how to [disable cookies](http://files.investis.com/info/disabling-cookies.html) in your browser. 

**Security  
** At John Cabot University we are committed to ensuring the security of your information and have put in place the necessary physical, technical, and administrative safeguards to prevent unauthorized access to any information we collect.  
All information gathered on the John Cabot Website is encrypted using 128-bit Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) and public-key encryption.  
The Site is a certified Thawte/Comodo secure site. Please visit [www.thawte.com](http://www.thawte.com/) or [www.comodo.com](http://www.comodo.com/ "www.comodo.com") for more information about the security certification program.  
Notwithstanding the foregoing, users and visitors to the JCU website should keep in mind that this site and all associated services are run on software, hardware and networks, any component of which may, from time to time, require maintenance or experience problems. 

**Sharing your information**  
We will not share your personal information with unaffiliated third parties except for certain explicit circumstances in which disclosure is required by law. 

**Third Party Sites**  
The JCU website provides links to external sites as a convenience. Please note that the University is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other sites linked within our website. 

**Confidentiality of Student Educational Records**  
All enrolled students at John Cabot University are protected under [the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)](http://www2.ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html) and [Italian privacy law.](http://www.garanteprivacy.it/home_en/italian-legislation) Read more about JCU’s FERPA practices here.

**Changes to Statement**  
We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time and will post the changes on this web page. 

**Questions?** Contact [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#1760727562677376637264577d787f79747675786339727362)
